(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
5th Anniversary Live Stellar Symphony
キキリキー！ホロライブEnglishの小鳥遊キアラでーす！
Kikiriki! It's Takanashi Kiara from Hololive English!
イェーイ、スバル先輩！
Yay, Subaru-senpai!
なんと、なんと、なんと！五周年記念だと聞いてお祝いに来ました！
I heard it's your 5th anniversary, so I came to celebrate!
おめでとうございまーす！
Congratulations!
五年間はマジで、特にこの世界ではめちゃくちゃ長いじゃないですか。
Five years is really long, especially in this world, isn't it?
なのに毎日毎日、もうデビューしたてな感じで頑張っている姿は、本当に本当に尊敬しています。
And yet, I truly respect how you work hard every day as if you just debuted.
スバル先輩のように毎日元気でいられたらいいな、私も頑張ります！
I hope I can stay as energetic as you every day, I'll do my best too!
スバル先輩、これからもホロライブの先輩、そしてホロ鳥の仲間として一緒に頑張ろうね！仲良くしてください。
Subaru-senpai, let's keep doing our best together as a Hololive senior and Holotori member!
そして何よりも、今からのライブを全力で頑張ってね！見てるよ！ファイト！
And most importantly, do your best in the upcoming live! I'm watching! Fight!
エイ、エイ、オー！
Ei-ei-oh!
ホロライブの大空スバルちゃん、五周年おめでとう！
Oozora Subaru-chan from Hololive, happy 5th anniversary!
どうやらライブもあるみたいじゃ。頑張ってね！
It seems there's a live too. Good luck!
また一緒にゲームで遊ぼう！
Let's play games together again!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
スバル先輩、五周年おめでとうございますでござる！
Subaru-senpai, happy 5th anniversary, de gozaru!
五、五、ござるの五でござるな！おめでとうございます！
Go, go, it's the 5 of gozaru! Congratulations!
最近はね、裏で一緒にFF14で遊ばせていただいたりとか、スト6やってるとこ見せてもらいつつお話ししたりとかしてて、
Lately, we've been playing FF14 together and chatting while I watch you play Street Fighter,
勝手にすごく距離が縮まったんじゃないかななんて思っています。
so I feel like we've gotten a lot closer.
いつも構っていただきありがとうございます。
Thank you for always hanging out with me.
スバル先輩のね、元気な姿とかダンスしてる姿は風真にとってお手本なので、
Subaru-senpai's energetic self and your dancing are a model for me,
これからも一緒に色んなことができたら嬉しいなと思っております。
so I hope we can do many things together from now on.
今日のライブも楽しみにしてます！
I'm looking forward to today's live!
ござるさんと一緒に応援してるでござる！
I'm cheering for you with Gozaru-san!
頑張ってください！いけるいける！スバル先輩ならいけるでござる！
Please do your best! You can do it! You've got this, Subaru-senpai!
スバル先輩、スバル先輩！スバル先輩、スバル先輩！
Subaru-senpai, Subaru-senpai! Subaru-senpai, Subaru-senpai!
お疲れ様です。火威青です。
Good job. It's Hiodoshi Ao.
スバル先輩ってもしかして……あ、五周年！五周年ですよね！おめでとうございます！
Subaru-senpai, are you perhaps... ah, 5th anniversary! Happy 5th anniversary!
いやマジめでたい。マジめでたいな。
Seriously, it's a big deal. It really is.
もしかしてこの後って……ライブ！そうですよね、ライブですよね！
Are you perhaps... doing a live next! Right, it's a live, isn't it!
いやめっちゃ楽しみ。マジ楽しみです。え、めっちゃ応援してますマジで。
Man, I'm so excited. I'm really looking forward to it. I'm rooting for you so much!
あ、めっちゃ応援してます。あ、スバル先輩！スバル先輩！
I'm rooting for you so much. Ah, Subaru-senpai! Subaru-senpai!
いや僕マジでスバル先輩のこと尊敬してて。
I really, truly respect Subaru-senpai.
そうなんです。スバル先輩って可愛いだけじゃなくて、ここが熱くて。いやマジハートが熱くて、かっけーなって思ってて。
Subaru-senpai isn't just cute, you've got passion. Your heart is so passionate and cool.
え、そう。だからめちゃめちゃ尊敬してて。あ、そうなんです。
Yes, exactly. That's why I respect you so much. Yes, that's right.
あ、あ、あ、スバル先輩！
A-A-A, Subaru-senpai!
いやマジでマジでマジで、めっちゃ尊敬してるマジで。
No, seriously, seriously, seriously, I respect you so much, seriously.
マジ、可愛いですね今日も。え、今日も可愛い。
Seriously, you're cute today too. Like, so cute today.
え、え、スバル先輩、あ、スバル先輩、めっちゃ尊敬してるからマジで。スバル先輩。
Uh, uh, Subaru-senpai, ah, Subaru-senpai, I really respect you so much, seriously. Subaru-senpai.
スバル先輩僕めっちゃ尊…ぱ…ぱ…スバ…セ…ゼッ…ア…マジ…
Subaru-senpai, I really res— pa— pa— Suba— se— zet— a— seriously—
あの…めっちゃ応援してます今日マジ、あと頑張ってください！
Um... I'm really rooting for you today, seriously, so please do your best!
スバちゃーん！
Suba-chaaan!
5周年ライブ開催おめでとうございます！うおー！
Congratulations on your 5th Anniversary Live! Whoooo!
ついにこの日が来たんだと、もう団長ニコニコなんですけど。
The day has finally come, and I'm just all smiles over here.
きっとね、画面の向こうにいるスバ友も同じ気持ちだと思います。
I'm sure the Subatomo on the other side of the screen feel the same way.
団長は今日は、スバ友のみんなに負けないぐらい、
Today, I'm going to make sure I don't lose to any of the other Subatomo,
画面の向こうで全力でペンライト振っていこうと思うので、
and I'll be waving my penlights behind the screen with everything I've got!
いや、本当に楽しみにしてます。
Seriously, I'm really looking forward to it.
オープニング前からたぎってるんですけど、
I've been fired up since before the opening even started,
今年はね、どんなライブになるのか、
and I'm wondering what kind of live it'll be this year.
スバちゃん毎年ライブ最高だから、もう今から楽しみです。
Suba-chan's lives are always the best, so I'm already excited.
うわー、楽しみ楽しみ楽しみ！
Wow, I'm so excited, so excited, so excited!
5周年ライブ、始まる始まる始まるー！
The 5th Anniversary Live is starting, starting, starting!
スバル！5周年おめでとう！ライブ頑張れ！
Subaru! Happy 5th Anniversary! Good luck with the live!
スバル！ライブ頑張れー！
Subaru! Good luck with the live!
スバル！ライブ頑張れよー！
スバル！ライブ頑張れよ！草
Subaru! Good luck with the live! LOL
スバル！ライブ頑張れ！頑張れ！頑張れ！頑張れ！頑張れーー！
Subaru! Good luck with the live! Good luck! Good luck! Good luck! Good luck!
3!
Three!
2!
Two!
1!
One!
LIVE START!!
いつもの一日から抜け出して
Break out of the usual daily routine
目が覚めるような冒険の舞台へ
To the stage of an eye-opening adventure
回る地球儀を目印に
With the spinning globe as our landmark
さあ今会いに行こう
Come on, let's go meet now
特別な一日に
On this special day
緑も揺れる新しい季節に
In the new season where even the greenery sways
一人見つめたブルーライト
A blue light I stared at alone
顔も知らない友達に
To friends whose faces I don't even know
耳慣れたクラスメイト
Classmates whose voices I've grown accustomed to
想定外の暮らし
An unexpected way of living
こんなんじゃない
It's not like this
予想した理想と真反対に
The complete opposite of the ideal I imagined
淡々と過ぎる毎日
Days that pass by uneventfully
でもやっと会えるね
But we can finally meet, can't we?
想像超え現実をまじまじ
Gazing intently at a reality beyond imagination
高鳴る胸
My pounding heart
抑えられない ああ
I can't hold it back, ah
約束の場所は
The promised place is...
夢見ていた場所
The place I was dreaming of
忘れられない一日が
An unforgettable day...
今始まる
...is starting now
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
The day I've been waiting for, today is a special day
日常から少しはみ出して
Stepping out a little bit from daily life
ほらシャッターを切って映し出せば
Look, if you press the shutter and project it,
どうしたってこぼれるような笑顔ばかり
No matter what, it'll be nothing but overflowing smiles
アドベンチャー
Adventure
描き出した
Sketched out
飛び乗ったコースターも
Even the coaster I jumped on
お揃いのカチューシャも
Matching headbands too
かけがえのない瞬間で溢れてる
Overflowing with irreplaceable moments
待ち時間さえも愛しく思える
Even the wait feels precious
次はどこに行こうか
Where should we go next?
軽やかに歩く
Walking lightheartedly
不思議なほどに気がつけば好きでいる時間
Curiously, before I knew it, I've loved this time
太陽が沈んだ街を飾る
Decorating the town where the sun has set
光が織りなすパレードに
In the parade woven with lights
心奪われ噛み締める
Heart stolen, I cherish it
あぁ本当にここに来れてよかったな
Ah, I'm so glad I could come here
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
Today, the day I've long-awaited, is a special day
いつも通りから飛び出して
Jumping out from the ordinary
ほらシャッターを切っても写せない
Look, even if you press the shutter, you can't capture
思い出がいつでも待っている
The memories that are always waiting
春も夏も秋も冬も
Spring, summer, autumn, and winter
この場所で見つけた笑顔が
The smiles I found in this place
キラキラといくつも積もっていく
Keep piling up, sparkling away
さあ次はいつ会いに行けるかな
Now, when can I go see you next?
限界のない冒険の舞台
A stage for limitless adventure
回る地球儀を目印に
With the spinning globe as our landmark
さぁ今会いに行こう 特別な1日に
Now, let's go see you, on this special day
あなたのアイドル サインはB
Your idol, the sign is B!
サインはB
作詞・作曲：オーイシマサヨシ
The Sign is B
Lyrics/Composition: Masayoshi Oishi
やっと会えたね嬉しいね
We finally met, I'm so happy
待ち遠しくて足をバタバタしながら
I was so excited, kicking my legs impatiently
今日楽しみで寝れなかったよ
I couldn't sleep because I was looking forward to today
緊張なんかしてる場合じゃない
This is no time to be nervous
1分1秒無駄になんてできない
Not a single minute or second can be wasted
さぁ始めましょう 君も君も君もお待たせ
Now, let's begin! You, and you, and you, sorry to keep you waiting!
さぁ手を鳴らせ いらっしゃいませ
Now, clap your hands! Welcome!
好きが集まる場所へようこそ
Welcome to the place where "love" gathers
日常はクロークの中
Leave your daily life in the cloakroom
ここに来たなら踊らにゃ損 損
If you've come here, it's a loss if you don't dance!
1人だろうが居まいが関係ない
Whether you're alone or not, it doesn't matter
箱が大きい小さいとか気にしない
I don't care if the venue is big or small
ちゃんと見えてる 君のペンライト
I can see it clearly, your penlight
今ふっと吹けば飛ぶような
Right now, like something that would blow away with a puff
小さな小さな才能だけど私を推してくれるのなら
It's a tiny, tiny talent, but if you'll support me
爆レスをあげる
I'll give you a huge response!
あなたのアイドル サインはB
Your idol, the sign is B!
普段と違う顔見せてよ
Show me a face different from your usual one
みんな今日は絶好調 どうだいなりふり構わずに
Everyone is in top form today! How about it? Without worrying about appearances!
ヒソヒソ笑われていても関係ない
Even if they're whispering and laughing, it doesn't matter
周りの目とかとか気にしない
I don't care about the eyes around me
ずっと強気よ 君のペンライト
I'm always confident! Your penlight...
風で世界が変わった私を阻んで
The world changed with the wind, obstructing me
1人にボッチを感じたとしてもあなたが笑っていてくれたら
Even if I felt all alone, if you're smiling for me
怖いものはないよ
There's nothing to be afraid of
見てよ見てよ 何か始まる 君との物語が
Look, look! Something is starting! Our story together!
あぁなんて素晴らしい景色だ
Ah, what a wonderful sight!
1人だろうが居まいが関係ない
Whether you're alone or not, it doesn't matter
箱が大きい小さいとか気にしない
I don't care if the venue is big or small
ちゃんと見えてる 君のペンライト
I can see it clearly, your penlight
今ふっと吹けば飛ぶような
Right now, like something that would blow away with a puff
小さな小さな才能だけど私を推してくれるのなら
It's a tiny, tiny talent, but if you'll support me
あなたが笑っていてくれたら
If you're smiling for me...
触れたら...
If I touch you...
爆風を浴びる
You'll be hit by a blast
あなたのアイドル
I'm your idol
サインはB！
The sign is B!
Chu!
あなたのアイドル サインはB
I'm your idol, the sign is B
（Hoi! Hoi!）
(Hoi! Hoi!)
ぺたぺたパンプスでサンサン空中　ワーッ！
Pitter-patter in my pumps, Sun-Sun mid-air. Wah!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
あなたにも忘れたいこと　悲しいこと
Things you'd rather forget, things that are sad...
あるのかしらね
I wonder if you have those too.
知らない映画なのに涙を流すのは
The reason I cry even at an unknown movie
ドラマチックが足りてないからよ
Is because I'm lacking drama in my life.
そんな風に使い古したこと　くだらないこと
Worn-out things like that, trivial things like that...
考えてばかりね
You're always thinking about them.
雨が上がれば　愛もその横顔も
When the rain lets up, love and that profile of yours
誰かのものになるでしょう
Will surely belong to someone else.
嘘っぱちのファンデーションも全部　今夜のためよ
Even this fake foundation is all for tonight.
なのになぜ一体全体どうしてどうして
なぜのでハテナ
So then, why on earth, why, oh why
is it such a question mark?
不安定なカンテラ　どこまで行けるかな
An unstable lantern, I wonder how far it can go.
あなた一切合切放り出しても　あー
Even if you throw everything away, ah...
冗談じゃないわ　トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
I'm not kidding, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって　どうにもなんないぜ
Even when the time comes, it won't do a thing.
曖昧な本当なんて　メランコリーに浸るだけ
Vague truths only sink you into melancholy.
私をさらって　今Take me, yeah!
Carry me away, now Take me, yeah!
はー　ちゃんちゃらおかしなハットバカでしょ
Ha, it's just ridiculous, a fool in a hat, right?
串がぴくともしないわ　実体のない感情放っておいたって
Not even a nudge; even if you leave empty feelings alone
策略なんてありゃせんのに何故
There's no strategy involved, so why?
ああ、もう懲り懲りよ　私の勝手なんて
Ah, enough already. My selfishness...
気質もじっと堪えて取り繕っては　とうとう臨界点
I endured and glossed over my nature, finally hitting the limit.
年がら年中リップサービス　どっかかましては
Lip service all year round, pulling stunts somewhere...
えきえき　どんがらがっしゃんフィールガールは涙の目にモニ
Exasperated; clatter, bang! The 'feel girl' has tears in her eyes.
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいで　あなたの話は一向に聞き取れない
With the music in my head now, I can't hear a word you're saying.
少しは真っ当なこと言って　Yeah!
Say something sensible for once, Yeah!
走り出すたって　全部　忘れさせてよ
Even if I start running, make me forget everything.
だけど一体全体どうしてどうして　なぜのでハテナ
But why on earth, why, oh why is it such a question mark?
不安定なカンテラ　消えないままでね
An unstable lantern, let it stay lit.
あなた＝両手ですくい違っても　あー
Even if 'you' slip through my cupped hands, ah...
冗談じゃないわ　トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
I'm not kidding, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって　どうにもなんないぜ
Even when the time comes, it won't do a thing.
曖昧な本当なんて　メランコリーに浸るだけ
Vague truths only sink you into melancholy.
私を今...
Me, now...
冗談じゃないわ　トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
I'm not kidding, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって　どうにもなんないぜ
Even when the time comes, it won't do a thing.
甲斐ないわ　感情なんてランドリーで通すだけ
It's useless; feelings just go through the laundry.
私と確かめ合ってイエロー・マジック
Let's confirm it together, Yellow Magic.
アイ・ヤー・ヤー　トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Ai-ya-ya, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって　どうにもなんないぜ
Even when the time comes, it won't do a thing.
曖昧な本当なんて　メランコリーに浸るだけ
Vague truths only sink you into melancholy.
私をさらって　今Take me, yeah!
Carry me away, now Take me, yeah!
はい！ということで、ちわーす！
ホロライブ2期生大空スバルでーす！
Alright! So, hello there!
It's Oozora Subaru from hololive 2nd Gen!
皆さん楽しんでくれてますかー？
Is everyone having a good time?!
今日はですね、大空スバル5thアニバーサリーライブに
来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much for coming to the
Oozora Subaru 5th Anniversary Live today!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しい！
I'm so incredibly happy!
でですね、今日はですね、
ぜひみんなにね、楽しんでもらって、
So, for today, I really want
everyone to have fun, and...
そしてですね、この上に出ている「#大空スバル5周年」で、
これでですね、ぜひXでポストしてください！
Also, please use the hashtag shown above,
"#大空スバル5周年", and post on X!
よろしくお願いします！
Please do that for me!
でですね、ちょっと息整えながら、せっかくなのでこのね、
So, while I catch my breath,
since we're here...
ポスト用の写真を、記念写真をね、ここで撮りたいと思います！
I'd like to take a commemorative photo
for you to post!
この衣装も久しぶりです。よいしょ。
It's been a while since I wore this outfit. There we go.
じゃあ、どんなポーズにしようかな...
Now, what kind of pose should I do...
じゃあさっきね、披露させていただいた
『サインはB』のこの決めポーズ！
Let's go with the signature pose
from 'Sign wa B' that I just performed!
ぜひね、皆さんこれをポストよろしくお願いします！
Everyone, please post this one!
はい！ということでですね、そして『サインはB』では、
ズバチョコルナたんのみんな、来てくれてありがとうございました！
Alright! Also, for 'Sign wa B',
SubaChocoLuna-tan, thank you all for coming!
ちょっとね、もうウリャウリャしてもらってね、
かなり嬉しかったです。ありがとね。
You guys really hyped it up for me,
and I was so happy. Thanks a bunch.
はい、ということでですね、
Alright, and with that...
ま、ここで前半のちょっとアイドルっぽいパートが１つ終わり。
the first 'idol-like' part of the first half is over.
そしてこっからはね、またちょっと何かが変わるかもしれませんで、
And from here on, things might change a little bit,
ぜひそのあたりもお楽しみにしていってください！
so please look forward to that as well!
それでは次の曲はこちら！
Now then, here is the next song!
気まぐれメルシィ
Kimagure Mercy
ほらほらまた始まった
Look, look, it's starting again
お得意の自己弁護言い訳
Your specialty: self-defense and excuses
でもね
But you see...
だって
Because...
ほらほらまた始まった
Look, look, it's starting again
ごめんからのキスのパターンの感じ
That 'Sorry' followed by a kiss routine
安易
Too easy
いつかあたしだけ そんな夢見たこともあったけど
I once dreamed it would be only me, but...
寂しい時だけ電話してもうんざりだわ
Calling me only when you're lonely... I'm sick of it
全然あたしに興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
君が好きなのは自分自身でしょ
The only one you love is yourself, right?
やっぱりあたしに興味ないじゃん
As I thought, you're not interested in me
その話もう聞き飽きたわ
I'm tired of hearing that story
そもそも大体あたしに興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you don't care about me
そうやってまた誤魔化して
Glossing it over like that again
Be my boy わがまま過ぎるベイビー
Be my boy, you're such a selfish baby
抱きしめてよね
Hold me tight, okay?
ほんと君はしょうもないな
You're really hopeless
甘いあたししょうがないな
And I'm too soft on you, I can't help it
泣いちゃって言ったって代わりゃしないや
Even if I cry and say it, nothing changes
もう少しくらいなら 踊ってもいいかもな
Maybe I could dance just a little longer
とろけて溶けてきたの
I'm starting to melt away
どんなアピールも意味ないし
No matter how I try to get your attention, it's meaningless
気づいてくれないけど
You don't even notice
あたしが寂しい時だって 会いに来て
Even when I'm lonely, come and see me
全然あたしに興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
どこがダメなのか教えてよ
Tell me what's wrong with me
やっぱりあたしに興味ないじゃん
As I thought, you're not interested in me
携帯ばかり弄ってさ
Just staring at your phone
そもそも大体あたしに興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you don't care about me
少し位期待させて
Give me a little hope
Lonely Girl 独り占めしてよベイビー
Lonely Girl, keep me all to yourself, baby
振り回さないで
Don't toy with me
Mayday Mercy 1,2 shall we dance?
Mayday Mercy 1, 2, shall we dance?
踊りましょう
Let's dance
早く手を繋いで
Hurry up and hold my hand
最後に一つだけ
Just one last thing
溺れる位愛してよ
Love me until I drown in it
全然あたしに興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
君が好きなのは自分自身でしょ
The only one you love is yourself, right?
やっぱりあたしに興味ないじゃん
As I thought, you're not interested in me
その話もう聞き飽きたわ
I'm tired of hearing that story
そもそも大体あたしに興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you don't care about me
そうやってまた誤魔化して
Glossing it over like that again
Get a last dance 覚悟は出来てるの
Get a last dance, I'm prepared
気まぐれメルシィ
Kimagure Mercy
お味はいかが？
How does it taste?
マーシャル・マキシマイザー
Marshall Maximizer
喧々、臨界実験につき合う朝
A noisy morning accompanying a critical experiment
14ポンド笑うベスト
A 14-pound laughing vest
「如何しようもないの」
"There's nothing I can do"
気が狂う人のフリをしてる君を見ている
I'm watching you pretend to be someone going mad
燦々、面倒だったから切り捨てた
Brilliant, I cut it off because it was a bother
4U型を攫う掃句
A sweeping phrase that snatches the 4U type
「申し訳ないけど」
"I'm sorry, but..."
すれ違いもなしに奪い寄せて遠回ししてる
Bringing it close without a miss, being indirect
「夜更かしはイドの暴走」
"Staying up late is the ego's rampage"
「目に焼き付いた胃の感光」
"The stomach's exposure burned into the eyes"
モラトリアム的人生
A moratorium-like life
最大公約数
The greatest common divisor
食べて すぐ寝て 牛になる
Eat, sleep right away, turn into a cow
起きて また寝て 人でなし
Wake up, sleep again, a good-for-nothing
マキシマイザー！ マキシマイザー！
Maximizer! Maximizer!
挙手で合図を待って 壊したってとっ強行
Wait for the signal by hand, force it even if broken
なんて事だ死んでしまう
Good grief, I'm going to die
だがツマミは回る ガンジガラメ
But the knob turns, bound hand and foot
サングコステラ！ サングコステラ！
Sangcostella! Sangcostella!
同一体 終いには
The same entity, in the end
同位体 終いには 取り戻したい
Isotopes, in the end, I want to take them back
全部 無間地獄へ 落ちる 落ちる
All of them fall, fall into Avici hell
But a 眩み Unbalance 乖離 Farewell
But a dazzling unbalance, divergence, farewell
安易な 演技に 降り出す アラーム
An alarm starts to ring at the easy acting
旧四ロンドを 微笑う 劣等
An inferiority complex laughing at the old quartet rondo
「如何しようもないから」気が狂っている 人の真似をしている 君へ
To you who are imitating someone who is going crazy because "there's nothing you can do about it"
「簡単」な 言葉 信じていたいなら 足りないの。
If you want to believe in "simple" words, it's not enough.
「申し訳ないなら」 既に 合う 音に 不意に 会話 求まんないよ
If you're "sorry," I'm not suddenly looking for conversation in sounds that already match
後悔は エゴの 暴走
Regret is the runaway of ego
瞳に 焼き付いた 青の 偶像
A blue idol burned into my eyes
食べて すぐ 寝て 丑に なる
Eat and go to sleep right away, and you'll become a cow
起きて また 寝て 人でなし？
Wake up and go back to sleep, are you not human?
「舞っちまうな、 マキシマイザー」
"Don't get swept away, Maximizer"
救世主 待って 焦がしたって FADE 流行
Waiting for a savior, even if you yearn for one, the FADE fashion
「なんてこった、生きてしまう」
"Good grief, I'll end up living"
疑い 恨み 逆巻く 惨事 また GATE
Doubts, resentment, surging disasters, again a GATE
マキシマイザー マキシマイザー 救い手 合って 焦がしたって テト強行
Maximizer, Maximizer, even if there's a savior and you yearn for them, the Teto enforcement
「なんてこった、死んでしまう」
"Good grief, I'll end up dying"
疑い つまみは 回る 完字 から 兵
Doubts, the knobs turn, from a complete character to a soldier
サンク・コスタ サンク・コステ
Cinq Costa, Cinq Coste
同位体 終いには 取り戻したいって
Isotopes, in the end, I want to take them back
全部 無間地獄へ 落ちる 落ちる
All of them fall, fall into Avici hell
But a 眩み Unbalance 乖離 Farewell
But a dazzling unbalance, divergence, farewell
マキシマイザー マキシマイザー
Maximizer, Maximizer
マキシマイザー
Maximizer
マキシマイザー マキシマイザー
Maximizer, Maximizer
あなたは 今 どこで 何を していますか？
Where are you now and what are you doing?
この 空の 続く 場所に いますか？
Are you in the place where this sky continues?
今まで 私の 心を 埋めていたモノ
The things that had been filling my heart until now
失って 初めて 気付いた
I only noticed after I lost them
こんなにも 私を 支えてくれていたこと
That you were supporting me so much
こんなにも 笑顔を くれていたこと
That you were giving me so many smiles
失ってしまった 代償は
The price I paid for losing it
とてつもなく 大きすぎて
Is unimaginably large
取り戻そうと 必死に
Desperately trying to get it back
手を 伸ばしても がくけれど
Even if I reach out and struggle
まるで 風のように すり抜けて
Like the wind, it slips through
届きそうで 届かない
It seems within reach, yet it's not
孤独と 絶望に 胸を 締め付けられ
My chest is tightened by loneliness and despair
心が 壊れそうに なるけれど
My heart is about to break, but...
思い出に 残る あなたの 笑顔が
Your smile that remains in my memories
私を いつも 励ましてくれる
Always encourages me
もう一度 あの頃に 戻ろう
Let's go back to those days once again
今度は きっと 大丈夫
This time, it'll surely be alright
いつも そばで 笑っていよう
Let's always be laughing by each other's side
あなたの すぐ そばで
Right there beside you
あなたは 今 どこで 何を していますか？
Where are you now and what are you doing?
この 空の 続く 場所に いますか？
Are you in the place where this sky continues?
いつものように 笑顔で いてくれますか？
Will you stay smiling as you always do?
今は ただ それを 願い続ける
For now, I'll just keep on wishing for that
カルマ
Karma
作詞・作曲：藤原基央
Lyrics/Composition: Fujiwara Motoo
ガラス玉ひとつ落とされた
A single glass bead was dropped
追いかけてもうひとつ落っこちた
I chased after it and another one fell
ひとつ分の陽だまりに
In a single sunny spot
ひとつだけ残ってる
Only one remains
心臓が始まった時
When my heart started beating
嫌でも人は場所を取る
Whether they like it or not, people take up space
奪われないように守り続けてる
I keep protecting it so it won't be taken away
汚さずに保ってきた
I've kept it clean
手でも汚れて見えた
But even my hands looked dirty
記憶を疑う前に
Before doubting my memories
記憶に疑われてる
I'm being doubted by my memories
必ず僕らは出会うだろう
We will surely meet
同じ鼓動の音を
With the sound of the same heartbeat
目印にして
As a guide
ここにいるよ
I'm right here
いつだって呼んでるから
Because I'm always calling for you
くたびれた理由が
When our worn-out reasons
重なって揺れる時
Overlap and sway
生まれた意味を知る
I'll know the meaning of being born
存在が続く限り
As long as existence continues
仕方ないから場所を取る
I have no choice but to take up space
ひとつ分の陽だまりに
In a single sunny spot
ふたつはちょっと入れない
Two people can't quite fit
ガラス玉ひとつ落とされた
A single glass bead was dropped
落ちた時何か弾き出した
Something popped out when it fell
奪い取った場所で光を浴びた
I basked in the light in the place I seized
数えた足跡など
The footprints I counted and such
気付けば数字でしかない
Are nothing more than numbers when I realize it
知らなきゃいけないことは
What I need to know
どうやら1と0の間
Is apparently between 1 and 0
初めて僕らは出会うだろう
We will meet for the first time
同じ悲鳴の旗を
With the flag of the same scream
目印にして
As a guide
忘れないで
Don't forget
いつだって呼んでるから
Because I'm always calling for you
重ねた理由を
When our piled-up reasons
二人で埋める時
Are filled by both of us
約束が交わされる
A promise will be exchanged
鏡なんだ僕ら互いに
We are mirrors to each other
それぞれのカルマを映すための
To reflect our respective karmas
汚れた手と手で触り合って
Touching each other with dirty hands
形がわかる
I can tell the shape
ここにいるよ
I'm right here
確かに触れるよ
I can definitely touch you
ひとり分の陽だまりに
In a single person's sunny spot
僕らはいる
We are here
忘れないで
Don't forget
いつだって呼んでるから
Because I'm always calling for you
同じガラス玉の内側の方から
From inside the same glass bead
そうさ必ず僕らは出会うだろう
That's right, we will surely meet
沈めた理由に十字架を立てる時
When we erect a cross over our submerged reasons
約束は果たされる
The promise will be fulfilled
僕らは一つになる
We will become one
はい！ということで披露した楽曲はカルマでした！
Yes! So the song I performed was 'Karma'!
いかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you like it?
ちょっとね、この部分は爆弾サーさんのね、
Well, for this part, with the help of Bakudan-sa...
構成もりもりのダンスにさせていただいたんですけども
I performed a dance with a lot of choreography
あ、この、えっと、マーシャル・マキシマイザーとか、あと、
Ah, this... um, 'Marshall Maximizer' and...
えっと、何だったかな？
um, what was it?
もういっぱい、いっぱい過ぎて忘れちゃったよ。
It's just too much, too much, and I forgot.
何だったんですけどね、
What was it...
ちょっと演出とかにもね、こだわってみたので、
but I also paid attention to the production,
ぜひともね、そのあたりもね、注意してみて、見てもらえたらとても嬉しいです！
so I'd be very happy if you could pay attention to those things as well!
このあともですね、
After this, also...
こだわった部分がたくさん、たくさんあるので、
there are many, many parts that I was particular about,
そこもね、そのあとの曲もぜひ楽しみにしてください！
so please look forward to those and the songs that follow!
ということで、いよいよライブも後半戦！
So, finally, the live is in its second half!
ということで次は、この曲です！
So next is this song!
聞いてください！
Please listen!
ブラック★ロックシューター どこへ行ったの？
Black★Rock Shooter, where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
ブラック★ロックシューター
作詞・作曲：ryo
Black★Rock Shooter
Lyrics & Composition: ryo
あとどれだけ叫べばいいんだろう？
How much more should I scream?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいんだろう？
How much more should I cry?
もうやめて 私はもう走れない
Stop it already, I can't run anymore.
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of is closing.
真っ暗で灯りもない
It's pitch black, with no light.
崩れかけたこの道で
On this crumbling road.
あるはずもないあの時の希望が
The hope from that time that shouldn't exist...
見えた気がした
...felt like it was visible.
どうして ブラック★ロックシューター 懐かしい記憶
Why, Black★Rock Shooter? Nostalgic memories.
ただ楽しかったあの頃を
Of those times when it was just fun.
ブラック★ロックシューター でも動けないよ
Black★Rock Shooter, but I can't move.
闇を駆ける星に願いを
A wish upon a star racing through the darkness.
もう一度だけ走るから
Because I'll run one more time.
怖くて震える声で呟く
Muttering with a voice trembling from fear.
私の名前を呼んで
Call my name.
夜明けを抱く空 境界線までの距離
The sky embracing the dawn, the distance to the boundary...
あと一歩届かない
...is still one step out of reach.
こらえた涙が溢れそうなの
The held-back tears feel like they're about to overflow.
今下を向かないで 止まってしまう
Don't look down now, or you'll come to a stop.
未来を生きていたいんだ わかったの
I want to live in the future, I understand now.
思い出して 強く 強く 信じるの
Remember, and believe strongly, strongly.
そうよ ブラック★ロックシューター 優しい匂い
That's right, Black★Rock Shooter, a gentle scent.
痛いよ 辛いよ 飲み込む言葉
It hurts, it's painful, words swallowed down.
ブラック★ロックシューター 動いてこの足！
Black★Rock Shooter, move, these legs!
世界を越えて
Beyond the world.
最初からわかっていた
I knew from the beginning...
ここにいることを
...that you were here.
私の中の全ての勇気が 火を灯して
All the courage inside me lights a fire.
もう逃げないよ
I won't run away anymore.
ブラック★ロックシューター 1人じゃないよ
Black★Rock Shooter, you're not alone.
声をあげて泣いたって構わない
It doesn't matter if you raise your voice and cry.
ブラック★ロックシューター 見ていてくれる
Black★Rock Shooter, you're watching over me.
今から始まるの 私の物語
My story starts from now.
忘れそうになったら この歌を
If I'm about to forget, this song...
歌うの
...I will sing.
スターライト
作詞・作曲：DIVELA
Starlight
Lyrics & Music: DIVELA
描いた　未知のキャンバス　重ねる景色
The canvas of the unknown I've painted, the overlapping scenery
繋いでみて　繰り返してくショット
Try connecting them, the repeating shots
揺らいだ　目の前に広がる世界
The world spreading out before my wavering eyes
星屑のメロディ　歌に乗せた
A melody of stardust, put into song
クラった鮮やかに　眩ませるように
Struck by the brightness, as if to dazzle
駆け抜けるよ　スターライト
I'll run through, Starlight
We can fight　そう僕らは　いつしか　夢の中惹かれて
We can fight, yes, we were drawn into the dream before we knew it
ただがむしゃらに　走り続けたよ
I just kept running recklessly
無限の宇宙に　響いた　君を照らす声は
Resonating in the infinite universe, the voice that shines on you
どこへだってキラリ　飛んで行けるんだ
Will sparkle anywhere, able to fly anywhere
愉快な　仲間と歩いた非日常
The extraordinary days I walked with cheerful friends
掴んでみて　指先の糸先
Try grabbing it, the thread at my fingertips
滲んでいく　目の前に広がった限界は
The limits that spread before my blurring eyes
みんなの声重ねて　ぶっ壊して
I'll overlap everyone's voices and smash through them
吸い込まれそうな　夜空を見上げて
Looking up at the night sky that seems to suck me in
今叫ぶよ　スターライト
I'll shout it now, Starlight
I wanna be　そう僕らは　いつでも　そばで笑い合って
I wanna be, yes, we were always laughing together by each other's side
溢れる声が　遠く木霊する
Our overflowing voices echo far away
願いの欠片を　灯した　君の腕を引いて
Lighting up the fragments of our wishes, I'll pull your arm
どこへだってキラリ　飛んで行けるんだ
Will sparkle anywhere, able to fly anywhere
ちょっと不安な日も　魔法をかけてハッピー
Even on slightly anxious days, cast a spell and be happy
百人力で乗り越えていけた
With the strength of a hundred, we could overcome it
あどあぶるに染まる　大空目掛けた
Dyed in adorable, aimed for the great sky
鼓動が弾んでく
Our heartbeats are bouncing
We can fly　そう僕らは　この日を　ずっと待ってたんだ
We can fly, yes, we've been waiting for this day forever
まだ冷めないで
Please don't cool down yet
スターライト　僕らは　止まらない　その光が消える
Starlight, we won't stop, until that light fades
一秒前まで　走り続けるよ
I'll keep running until the very last second
無限の宇宙に　響いた　君を照らす声を
Resonating in the infinite universe, the voice that shines on you
強く抱いてキラリ　輝いて行け
Hold it tight and sparkle, go on shining
Yeah...
Parade, Parade, Parade!　輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! It's shining
呼び合う声を合図に
With our voices calling to each other as the signal
Parade, Parade, Parade!　探しにゆく
Parade, Parade, Parade! We're going to search
スタートは　何度だって
The start is anytime
Our Bright Parade
作詞・作曲・編曲：堀江晶太
Lyrics, Music, & Arrangement: Shota Horie
ただ、独り言を綴った
I just wrote down my monologues
ただ、始まりたくて走った
I just ran because I wanted to begin
遠く、暗がりに灯った
Far away, lit in the darkness
それは、眩しすぎた名前
That was a name far too bright
それは 眩しすぎる光
It is a light too dazzling
それは 優しすぎる思い出 もっと
It is a memory too kind, more...
近づけと 手を伸ばした
...as I reached out my hand to get closer
思いがけず 結び合った
Unexpectedly, we were joined together
ほら 今 迷子は
Look, now the lost child...
僕等になった
...has become "us."
Parade, Parade, Parade, 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade, it's shining!
悔しさも 愛しさも
Regret, and even affection,
連れておいで
bring them along.
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings, we can take flight.
ささやかな祈りは光
A small prayer is light,
終わりなき響き出し
a never-ending resonance...
君を 見つけたこと
...that I found you.
胸を張れるよ
I can be proud of it.
ここから これから
From here, from now on,
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
まだ 頼りない予感を
With a still unreliable premonition,
歌おう
let's sing.
恥ずかしくなんてないよ
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
誰も解けない イマジナリー
An imaginary that no one can solve.
いつか また逢える おまじない
A spell to meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
A story that started at zero that day.
数え切れない 言の葉
Countless words...
数えるような想いじゃないさ
...aren't feelings meant to be counted.
ほら 今 僕等を
Look, now let's call "us"...
一つと呼ぼう
...as one.
Parade, Parade, Parade, 美しいんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade, it's beautiful!
許し合える刻が
The moments we can forgive each other,
夜は きらめく
the night sparkles.
雨 晴れ 晴れ また同じ空
Rain, shine, shine, the same sky again.
似つかわしい旅路とは
As for a fitting journey,
君と在ることさ
it's being with you.
君と在ることなんだ
It's being with you.
「ただいま」を聞けば
When I hear "I'm home,"
「おかえり」って叫ぶよ
I'll shout "Welcome back!"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that obvious?
Parade, Parade, Parade, 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade, it's shining!
暗がりを満たすのは
What fills the darkness is...
君だ 僕だ
...you, and me!
Parade, Parade, Parade, 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade, it's shining!
悔しさも 愛しさも
Regret, and even affection,
連れておいで
bring them along.
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings, we can take flight.
ささやかな祈りは光
A small prayer is light,
終わりなき響き出し
a never-ending resonance...
君と 飛び込んでゆく
...as I dive in with you.
素敵なスタートさ
It's a wonderful start.
ここから これから
From here, from now on,
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
はい！ということで！
Yes! So!
2期生のみんなとね、Starlight、そして Our Bright Parade...
With all the 2nd Gen members, we performed "Starlight", then "Our Bright Parade"...
そしてですね、スバルで Black-Rock Shooter を歌わせていただきました！
...and then, I, Subaru, performed "Black-Rock Shooter"!
おお～！
Whoa~!
ちょっとね、結構こう盛りだくさんな内容だったと思うんですけど...
It was quite a jam-packed segment, I think...
もう本当にね、一緒に踊ってくれたバックダンサーの皆さん、そしてね、2期生のみんな、ありがとうございました！
...so truly, to the back dancers who danced with us, and the 2nd Gen members, thank you so much!
はい、ということで！ここでなんと！
Yes, so! Here, believe it or not!
活動5周年記念グッズが出ます！
My 5th Anniversary Commemorative Goods are coming out!
こちら！
Here they are!
それではね、あの、一つずつ見ていきたいと思います。
Now then, I'd like to take a look at them one by one.
まずはこちら！ お、出てますね。
First, this one! Oh, it's up.
B2タペストリー！ これはですね、しぐれういかーちゃんの描き下ろしの、B2タペストリーです。
The B2 Tapestry! This is a B2 tapestry with a new illustration by Shigure Ui-karchan.
ぜひね、お部屋に一緒に飾ってください。ちょっとね、服なんかもね、あの、ちょっとこう特別のね、5周年っぽい、
Please display it in your room. The clothes are also a bit special, very 5th anniversary-like,
ドレスみたいなの着て、可愛い！
wearing something like a dress. It's cute!
そしてスバルドダックもね、こうなんかカゴに入れられてお花と一緒に、なんか愛らしい感じになってます。
And Subarudo Duck is there too, in a basket with flowers, looking quite lovely.
ぜひね、一緒に飾ってみてください。
Please try displaying it.
そしてですね、続いてこちら！
And then, next is this!
しゅばっ！ジャージ！ ということでね、スバルといえばまあジャージなんですけど、
Shuba! Jersey! So, when you think of Subaru, you think of jerseys,
まあスバルもね、これを着てね、ダンスレッスンやね、スタジオなんかに着たいと思うのでね、
and I want to wear this to dance lessons and the studio,
ぜひみんなも一緒に着てお揃いにしましょう！ はい、ジムなんかに着ていくのもおすすめです。
so let's all wear it together and match! Yes, I also recommend wearing it to the gym.
はい、そして次はこちら！
Yes, and next is this!
しゅばっ！キャップ！ これはマジでいい！もう本当に、これをスバルが欲しくて作ったまであるんです。
Shuba! Cap! This is seriously good! Honestly, I made this because I wanted one myself.
しゅばっ！キャップ
サイズ：フリーサイズ（頭囲約57～61cm）
素材：綿・PE
Shuba! Cap
Size: Free size (Head circ. approx. 57–61 cm)
Material: Cotton, PE
けど、これに『SHUBA!』って書いてあるね。
But it has "SHUBA!" written on it.
スバルの推しだよということをアピールしながら使えるキャップとなっております。黒なのでね、
It's a cap you can use while showing that you're a Subaru fan. Since it's black...
ぜひね、あくたんにもお勧めです。あくたんよかったら被ってねということで、
I highly recommend it to Akutan as well. "Akutan, please wear it if you like."
それでは続いてこちら！
And now, for the next one!
しゅばっ！靴下
サイズ：約25～28cm
素材：綿・ポリエステル・ポリウレタン
Shuba! Socks
Size: Approx. 25–28 cm
Material: Cotton, Polyester, Polyurethane
しゅばっ！靴下！ということでですね、
Shuba! Socks! So...
これはですね、スバルが靴下が欲しくてね。すいません、スバルが欲しかったから作りました。
Well, Subaru wanted socks. Sorry, I made them because I wanted them.
ぜひみんなもこの可愛いスバルダックのワンポイント靴下を履いて、
Everyone, please wear these cute Subaru-duck one-point socks,
学校や、お仕事や、ジムや、レッスンに、よかったら行ってみてください！
and head to school, work, the gym, or lessons!
はい、そしてなんとですね、フルセットは！
Yes, and what's more, for the full set!
フルセット購入特典
箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカード
Full Set Purchase Bonus
Postcard with foil-stamped replica signature & message
箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りとなっております！
It comes with a foil-stamped replica signature and message!
こちらはですね、しぐれうい母ちゃんの描き下ろしポストカードです！
This is a postcard with a new illustration by Shigure Ui-kaachan!
そしてですね、なんと今回、数量限定ではありません！
And, surprisingly, it's not a limited quantity this time!
よろしくお願いします！数量限定ではないので、みんな買えるタイミングで買ってみてください！
Thank you! Since it's not limited, please buy it whenever you can!
はい、そしてもう一つ、お知らせがあります！
Yes, and I have one more announcement!
なんとですね、このあと、22時に新曲のPVが公開されます！
Guess what, the music video for the new song will be released at 22:00!
新曲！新曲！さあ！
New song! New song! Now!
最後のね、曲に行こうと思うんですけど、最後の曲は新曲です。
I'm going to perform the last song, and it's a new one.
この曲はですね、まあスバルも5年間活動してきたわけなんですけど、
For this song, well, Subaru has been active for five years now,
この5年間のスバルの活動を支えてくれたファンの皆さんやメンバーの皆さんのことを考えて作りました。
and I made it while thinking about the fans and members who have supported me over these five years.
5周年をこうやってみんなと迎えられて、本当に嬉しいです。いつもたくさんの応援ありがとう、
I'm truly happy to celebrate the 5th anniversary with everyone like this. Thank you for all your support.
というですね、感謝を込めて、一生懸命歌いたいと思うので、よかったら聞いてください！
With that gratitude, I'll sing my heart out, so please listen!
じゃあ、行くぞ！歌うぞ！よっしゃ！
Alright, let's go! I'm gonna sing! Let's do this!
それでは聞いてください。Stellar Symphony。
Now, please listen. Stellar Symphony.
手を伸ばせば 届きそうな
If I reach out my hand, it seems reachable
空に輝く 希望の光
The light of hope shining in the sky
Stellar Symphony
作詞・作曲・編曲：やぎぬまかな
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Yaginuma Kana
星は巡り合う 願い求め
Stars encounter each other, seeking wishes
奇跡と出会うその日を
Toward that day we meet with a miracle
寄り添い輝く 愛を抱え
Shining close together, embracing love
煌めく熱は空駆け伝う
The sparkling heat spreads across the sky
きらり 光る 星は集い 私 囲まれていたんだ
Twinkle, twinkling stars gather, I was surrounded by them
願い奏でる空に
In the sky where wishes harmonize
一つ 二つ 輝く意味を 灯して
One by one, lighting up the meanings of shining
繋いで 光る明日描いて
Connecting them, painting a bright tomorrow
星は回る 愛を乗せて 私のすべて 届きますように
Stars turn, carrying love, may everything of mine reach you
願い込め 歌うから 星を撫でて I love you
Singing with a wish, stroking the stars, I love you
大空を 紡ぐのは 君と私
The ones spinning the vast sky are you and I
通わせて 想いを 星を繋げ Shine with you
Exchanging our thoughts, connecting the stars, Shine with you
描いた 夢 目指して 歩もう
Let's walk toward the dreams we've painted
またたく きらり 光る 星は満ちて 私 照らし出されていたんだ
Twinkle, twinkling stars are full, I was being illuminated
確かな奇跡 描いて
Painting a certain miracle
涙さえも 時を焚べて
Burning even tears into time
光って
Shine on
手を伸ばせば 届きそうな
If I reach out my hand, it seems reachable
空に輝く 皆の光
Everyone's light shining in the sky
共に歩んだ事 君がくれた愛を
The path we walked together, the love you gave me
幾重の運命を 抱き締めて
Embracing the layers of destiny
私 輝くから あなたを照らすから
Because I will shine, because I will illuminate you
大空を 紡ぐんだ みんなと
We spin the vast sky, together with everyone
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
アドベンチャー
Adventure
サインはB
Sign wa B
トゥキウッ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
気まぐれメルシィ
Kimagure Mercy
you
カルマ
Karma
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
スターライト
Starlight
Our Bright Parade
Stellar Symphony
5周年ありがとう！
Thank you for the 5th Anniversary!
スバ友のみんな
To all the Subatomos,
君と一緒に、これからも光り輝けますように!!!
May you and I continue to shine together from now on!!!